Michael designs the new neighborhood.
The Bad Place gets to
choose the four new humans.
The other residents will be Janet Babies.
You know, if we pooled our resources,
we could be done in two
shakes of a lamb's Derek.
Thanks, Derek.
When you fail, the four humans
will be tortured for all eternity.
But guess who's going
to be doing the torturing?
We built a Michael suit.
I can't do it. It's too scary.
- Hi, John, I'm the Architect.
Come on in.
The Bad Place didn't
pick the worst people.
They picked the people
who would be the worst for us.
You need to erase my
memory and reboot me.
Hi, Chidi, I'm Eleanor. Come on in.
Wow! Just... wow!
It's perfect. Everything is just perfect.
I am so, so happy.
I'm glad you like it.
It's so quaint... it feels cozy,
but also vibrant and limitless.
I can't believe how...
How utterly, completely,
100% perfect everything is...
You know, let's keep this moving.
Oh, yeah, sure.
Here is your new home,
complete with two
of your favorite things:
Floor-to-ceiling bookshelves and...
Reading lights! I love reading lights.
They are great for reading.
Your magic philosophy library
contains every text ever written,
from Aristotle to Zeno.
And, oh, check this out.
Um, hold out your hand.
And think about a book.
Whoa-ho-ho-ho!
I can summon philosophy
books like Thor's hammer.
This is literally my number one dream.
Also... ow!
That hurt.
Well, I have a lot to attend to.
Um... welcome to the Good Place, Chidi.
Thank you so much.
Ah... and I'm... I'm sorry.
This has been so overwhelming,
I-I forgot your name.
- Eleanor.
- Eleanor, right.
Sorry. Eleanor, Eleanor, Eleanor.
- Now I'll never forget.
- Well, you might!
Okay, can we not...
Oh, Eleanor, you did a brave thing
and I am embracing you
and I shall not let you go.
And I'm also embracing you
because this feels warm
and my hands are cold.
Guys, I'm good. Honestly.
Wasn't even as bad as I thought.
I mean,
who cares if he doesn't remember my name?
Oof... I mean, cool.
Good save, bud.
Let's just concentrate
on the next resident,
who gets here in... six minutes.
Wait. I need to say something.
I know this seems bleak
and it feels like we're all doomed
and therefore humanity is doomed.
You needed to say that?
The point is,
I believe that we're destined to succeed.
There is nothing that the
Bad Place can throw at us
that we can't handle,
because we are an incredible,
inspiring, brilliant group of...
Supercharged, d-bag, ass-wiping maniacs.
I mean, look at you.
I am so proud
of how disgusting and cruel you all are.
You suck.
You all suck donkey butts.
Tahani...
so, so smart, and sophisticated.
She was the only one
who was able to talk me
out of that goatee.
Well,
I lost that battle with Robert Downey Jr.,
and I'll be damned if I lose it with you.
Bambadjan... such an unbelievable dingus.
- Aww, thanks, boss.
- And Val.
Who's a bigger skid mark than Val?
Maybe your mom.
Classic.
We have Janet,
who can do literally anything.
She made all the other
people in the neighborhood.
- Not people.
- We have me,
who had a momentary setback,
but I'm feeling great now.
And that was a while ago.
Most of you don't even remember it,
probably.
We have Jason,
who can...
And marching us into battle,
our fearless leader,
the pride of Phoenix, Arizona,
Eleanor Shellstrop!
- Yay, Eleanor!
- Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Technically, the pride of Phoenix
is a life-size statue of Alice Cooper
made from cigarette butts.
It's outside City Hall.
But thank you for the kind words.
With this team,
there's no problem we can't solve.
There is no problem we can't create.
And believe me,
we are gonna create some a-problems.
So let's kick things off with
our official Bad Place song.
♪ 1-877-KARS for Kids ♪
♪ K-A-R-S, Kars for Kids ♪
- Ooh, are we singing?
- Shut up, Glenn.
I think you look great.
Professional, serious.
A proper team leader.
It does make me feel authoritative,
like that chick from "Law and Order."
Well, boys,
looks like we got ourselves an SVU.
I've never seen the show.
Okay, who we got next?
Linda? Come on in.
So you, Linda Johannsen,
are in the Good Place.
That's nice.
I know this can be a little overwhelming,
but you'll get used to it.
Do you have any questions?
Is there a fitness center?
There can be,
plus literally anything else
you could possibly wish for.
Just in case we weren't clear,
this is the Good Place.
A state of eternal happiness.
Paradise.
That's nice.
I like that.
So the Bad Place sent
Simone to mess with Chidi,
John to mess with Tahani...
Do you think they sent Linda
to mess with Jason? She's from Norway...
Is Norway, like, the opposite of Florida?
All I know is she's boring.
She makes Neutral Janet
look like Disco Janet.
Disco Janet was around for a while,
years ago.
She was great.
I mean, she was a lot,
but she was fun.
Actually, that's a good idea.
Let's unload this dead weight.
Janet?
- Hi, there.
- Linda, this is Janet.
If you want anything at all,
Janet can bring it to you.
Watch.
Janet, can I have a baby elephant
made of pure light
that tells you true secrets
about the universe?
Shirley Temple killed JFK.
See? Anything you want from Janet?
Can I have
a peppermint?
Sure.
I'm gonna go over there now.
Stonehenge was a sex thing.
Brent? Come on in.
So you, Brent Norwalk, are dead.
Dead? Really?
Well, that blows.
Ah, you know what,
maybe it's a good thing, actually.
Some journalist was poking around,
calling all these ladies
who used to work for me.
You can't even make a joke these days!
Everything is so PC.
And I was an equal-opportunity offender,
okay?
I made jokes about everybody,
and by the way,
I'm the furthest thing from racist.
My dentist was a black woman.
I just think people need to loosen up.
So, where am I, exactly?
- The Good Place.
- Oh, cool.
Good.
So, Brent, I see from your file
you were in the materials business.
Oh, yeah, big time.
Strings, chords, vinyl,
synthetics, rubber...
We do vulcanized now, so that's huge.
Plus metals...
aluminum, brass, copper... what else...
- Steel?
- No, not steel.
Steel's a sucker's game.
Polymers, coatings, internals...
You crack open an HVAC?
That is all us.
Is there golf here?
There freaking better be.
Okay, well,
why don't you explore around a bit
while I go far away
and if you need anything,
you can always ask Janet.
Janet?
Hi, there. How can I help you?
Oh, a secretary. Great.
- Not a secretary.
- Fine, fine.
Executive assistant.
Here we go with all the
terms we gotta learn, right?
Vice-president of helping.
Captain Marvel.
- You know what I'm saying.
- Oh, I'm not part of this.
Let me show you around.
Well,
Linda must be here for Jason because
Brent is definitely here to
annoy the fork out of me.
Everyone,
you may remember Matt from accounting.
Used to be in charge of the
Weird Sex Things Department.
Now the Judge has
assigned him to our project.
And I am thrilled to be here.
I mean, the things I had to read about...
The things people put in other things...
So I'll be monitoring
the four new humans.
A modified point system
will be applied to their actions
for the next year,
and then we'll know how much
better or worse their behavior is
than when they were alive.
But no one will be able
to see what's happening
in real time.
Good luck saving humanity
from eternal doom.
Okay, forget about all that stuff.
For this first week,
all we need to do is figure out
what the fork is up with these benches.
So, I made this.
We start 'em out on this side,
because we're like, "What's her deal?"
And when we feel we have
a handle on who they are,
what makes them tick,
we move them to this side...
Party time.
We already know a lot about Simone
so
Boom, see?
One down, three to go.
Let's go figure out the others.
We can do this. On three.
Dead eyes, eat hearts, can't lose.
Ah, sorry. Old Bad Place rally cry.
Aww, aww.
Janet! He's walking around again.
Yeah, I see that.
Derek, what are you doing here?
You're supposed to stay at Mindy's.
I can't help it.
I'm just such a proud daddy Derek.
I mean, will you look at
all these beautiful babies that we made?
She made them, dude.
You barely did anything.
Probably just, like, made all the butts.
I did make all the butts.
I made that butt...
- I made that butt...
- Right.
I made both those butts.
Derek, you have to stay at Mindy's house.
What if one of our new
humans sees you and starts
asking questions about
the weirdo in the tux?
Say no more.
I shall remove myself forthwith,
with my pickled potable.
But before I leave,
can I have a hug in celebration
of everything that we created?
- Okay.
- Aww.
That feels so... Derek.
Oh.
You are all, simply put, good people.
The point of the video is
to make them all confront
what kind of people they were on earth.
Keep a close eye on our four subjects.
Try to gauge their reactions, you know?
The subtlest glances,
the tiniest flinches.
What about shaking someone by the head?
- What does that mean?
- Oh, boy.
Hey, Simone,
everything okay?
Yeah, well, no...
well, actually, it doesn't matter.
None of this is real.
Sorry?
I'm a neuroscientist,
so I get what's going on here.
You know, clearly,
I was in some kind of horrible accident,
I'm on my deathbed, and this entire thing
is just a hallucination
constructed by my damaged brain
as it slowly shuts down.
It's not real,
so I'm just gonna wander around
until I wake up or die.
See you later,
figments of my imagination!
She's just gonna go get some popcorn
from the... river.
There's a popcorn river.
I'll show you guys later.
Uh, she said keep going without her,
so let's roll it.
Janet, make a popcorn river.
Everyone else,
meet at Mindy's in ten minutes.
Well... we're off to a fantastic start.
I told the other humans
that adjusting to the afterlife
was tricky, blah, blah, blah.
Seemed like they bought it.
What if Simone is right, though?
What if we are just Thin
Mints of her imagination?
Jason, remember you're a monk.
Even here where no one can see?
Mm-hmm, sometimes, yeah.
I wish I could stay and help,
but this system is so complex
that if I lose concentration
for even one billionth
of a second, the entire neighborhood
could collapse in on
itself like a dying star.
Also, Brent wants a BLT.
Simone's reaction is fairly common.
When I worked in the Bad Place,
some people just wouldn't
believe it when they
heard they were dead.
How did you convince them?
They'd usually come around
by the third or fourth
day of mouth fleas.
Obviously not an option here.
But,
if Simone doesn't think this is real,
she definitely won't
become a better person.
Who can convince her that
this actually is the afterlife?
We need someone
authoritative and reassuring,
like...
Nelson Mandela or Sir Patrick Stewart
or Arianna Huffington.
Really any of my old
racquetball partners would do.
Oh, I know who it should be.
If you say Blake Bortles,
I'm gonna slap you a lot.
Chidi!
I believe everything Chidi ever tells me
because of his brain and how he looks
like one of those owls
that graduated from college.
Of course.
Time to activate our
ethical sleeper agent
and introduce him to Simone.
Eh, I don't know, Simone isn't struggling
with a philosophy problem.
She's just, you know, like...
being silly.
I'll talk to her.
Tahani, I need your advice.
Derek is trying to move in on Janet.
I can just feel it.
Jason, Janet might not have
as much time for you as she used to,
but your relationship's on solid ground.
What do Janet and Derek
have in common anyway?
I mean, she did create him
out of the essence of herself.
Okay, fine, they share one thing.
Everything.
But if Derek is trying
to get under your skin,
you just have to rise above it.
All my favorite things
rise above other things,
like private airships
or my own head.
Look, I know this can be disorienting.
Okay, one moment, you're on Earth, alive,
eating queso like it's soup
and trying to guess your
neighbor's Wi-Fi password,
and the next, you're here...
Your face feels so much like a face.
I'll take that as a compliment.
Look,
I wasn't a particularly religious person,
but...
this just doesn't feel like heaven.
It's much more likely that I'm in a coma,
and my brain has invented all this.
Like the flowers.
Those are probably
just the "get well" flowers
in my hospital room.
Man, I was popular.
Well,
I can promise you the Good Place is real.
Think about what I said.
And in the meantime,
there's a fun welcome party tonight.
Dress up.
Have Janet make you
whatever outfit you'd like.
Eleanor!
Look what my brain did!
It's not real and neither are you.
♪ I'm in a coma and
none of this is real ♪
Okay, I know this is bad
and we need a new approach,
but... she is wearing the
hell out of those foam fingers.
Roo-da-toot-toot
Dude! Janet told you to stay at Mindy's.
I know,
I just came to mix myself a Derek,
and then I'll be on my way.
Before you leave, I want to call a truce.
Derek?
Feel like you're trying to get
under my skin, but it's okay.
I've decided to rise above it.
Well spoken, Mr. Mendoza.
Let me say in response...
I will
destroy you.
Janet is, and always will be,
my mommy-girlfriend.
You have crossed the Rubicon now, pal.
Mmm...
Okay, status report.
What have we learned about Linda?
Little, I'm afraid...
I tried talking to her,
but it was the dullest
conversation I have ever had,
and this is coming from
someone who once split a Xanax
with Peter Sarsgaard.
Frankly, I'm glad she's boring.
We have enough to worry about.
How is Brent doing?
- About the same, I'd say.
- Princeton.
Graduated in the top half of
the bottom half of my class.
Rowing team, sailing team,
class president.
I hung out with all those guys.
Okay, and John,
our favorite gossip columnist?
Luckily, before I died, I pumped my face
with six vials of Juvederm.
I'm hoping that my corpse
looks like a waxed tile floor.
My ex-boyf is going to be supes jel.
Okay, well, I'm gonna do a loop.
Trying to see who gets me.
Our biggest liability
right now is Simone.
Let's try to keep the three
of them away from her.
We can't wait any longer.
We have to introduce Simone to Chidi.
Why? I-I think she's doing great.
See, she's getting all the cake-pushing
out of her system.
I know it's painful to
think of the two of them
connecting,
but Chidi made an incredible sacrifice.
He had his memories erased
so he could help people.
And if we don't let him help Simone,
it'll be all for nothing.
Fine.
Stupid... ethical
reasonable argument.
I wish you were a cake. Push you over.
Are you still muttering?
No! I stopped.
Stupid, good-hearing, reformed demon...
Wow.
Oh!
Hey there, Simone.
Shoving people in the pool, huh?
Yeah, just testing the laws of physics
here in my nonsense brain jail.
Who's this?
Uh, this is Chidi Anagonye.
He was a professor of
ethics and moral philosophy,
so I figured he might be able to help...
Chidi Anagonye, that sounds so familiar.
Where did you teach?
St. John's University in Sydney.
Of course!
I used to teach there.
I must've seen his name
on the faculty list and
now my dying brain
is just leaking out random information.
Oh, the human mind is truly incredible!
♪ I want something else ♪
♪ To get me through this ♪
♪ Semi-charmed kind of life, baby, baby ♪
Look, sorry, uh, what...
What's happening now?
When I was a kid, my CD alarm clock broke
and it used to wake me
up to that song every day,
so now I'm singing it to
try and wake myself up.
Okay, well, nice meeting you.
Nice to meet you too, cute guy generated
by my rapidly decaying temporal lobe.
♪ Doo, doo, doo, doo-do-do-doo ♪
♪ Doo, doo, doo ♪
Hey...
You know,
it's bad enough you guys have taken over
my house for a year and I've had to move
into the attic, but now I have to walk in
to find Darth Vader's turd
in the middle of my living room.
I mean, what is this?
No time to explain.
Also, I kind of forgot.
Where is Derek's plunger?
The one that kills him.
Yeah, I used to do this whenever I needed
some alone time.
Once, I rebooted him
just because he was breathing super loud.
Then, when he woke up,
he was like, "I don't breathe."
So I don't know what I heard.
That was on me.
Well, I'm doing this because
he's trying to steal my girlfriend.
Yeah, you don't need to justify it.
Again, I do it all the time.
No, no, no, Mindy,
please wait, don't kill me!
Oh... it's you?
Okay, well,
you certainly don't have the Dereks to...
Yeah!
Oh, it's always good.
♪ Doo-do-do-doo, doo, doo, doo ♪
You know what, Simone?
Think of it this way.
If this is really all a hallucination,
doesn't it seem kind of basic?
I mean, surely,
your brain would imagine something
weirder than just a nice cocktail party?
Oh, you mean like that?
Attention, I have been Dereked.
That's probably my doctor.
I must be flat lining.
Oh, this is all in my head.
I'm gonna go eat a knife.
Attention. Murder has been me.
Let me get this straight:
Derek "made mean eyes at you,"
so you went to Mindy's
house and murdered him?
Yeah, dog, but his eyes were really mean.
You're probably thinking this,
but they were more like this...
Jason, why did you kill Derek?
I had to get his giant
head out of the sky
before any of the humans could see,
and it was not easy.
You have to push his plunger and his nose
at exactly the same time.
I was scared Derek was
trying to slide into your DMs.
I hate being scared. It's... it's scary.
I don't have time for this.
I am running a neighborhood
and its residents,
and Eleanor just casually orders me
to make popcorn rivers,
and Brent won't stop
calling me for stuff.
Ugh!
Are we still boyfriend-not-a-girlfriend?
We'll talk about it later.
Okay,
executive decision: Forget about Simone.
Janet,
make sure she doesn't come in contact
with the other humans.
Let's focus on Linda.
We ought to be able to figure her out
if we can just liven her up a bit.
We'll just, like, sprinkle some cocaine
on her peppermints or something.
Does anyone else find it suspicious
that the Bad Place sent someone so dull?
No, it makes perfect sense to me.
They are trying to drive us insane
by giving us a big boring
glob of plain yogurt.
Tomorrow morning,
we start Operation Linda.
Okay, you heard the lady.
We'll meet in the town
square bright and early.
- Janet, set up for Flying Day.
- Cool.
I'm not busy or anything,
so that'll be easy.
Off you go.
Whoo-hoo!
Ugh, being a parent is exhausting.
Never conjure 300 children
from the essence of your being.
You will have, like, zero free time.
Linda,
how are you enjoying the Good Place?
It's good.
Everyone's flying.
You don't want to go flying any higher?
No, thanks.
Oh, well, okay.
Says in your file that you like knitting.
Would you like to do
some knitting right now?
No, thanks.
Is there another activity
you'd like to do now?
You also enjoyed listening to birds.
Man, Linda, you don't even look at them?
Let's go hear some birds.
What do you say?
I'm gonna go get another peppermint.
Come on, Lins.
You can have literally
anything you could poss...
What the...
Okay, so...
Maybe she's less boring than I thought.
So let me get this straight, Shawn:
You sent a demon in
disguise as one of the subjects?
Yes, he did, Your Honor.
Luckily,
none of the other test subjects saw
the mess he made,
but he put the experiment at risk
and he attacked me and Eleanor.
And I'm sorry, where's your shirt?
I think it got stuck in the skin suit.
Well, keep it there.
Damn it, Chris,
you were supposed to
slowly undermine them
and gradually sabotage the experiment,
not just go ham on day two,
you fart plume.
I told you, I'm not an actor.
And when you get back here,
you won't be anything.
Okay, fine, yes, busted.
I'm a rascal.
We'll come pick him up and replace him
with an actual human.
Oh, you will do
nothing of the sort, mon ami.
This outrageous act must be punished.
Chidi will be the fourth
subject in this experiment.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
He's perfect because he's already had
his memories erased.
Although you can't erase that booty,
know what I'm saying, blondie?
All due respect, Your Honor,
keep it in your robe.
What she means is thank you,
Your Honor, we accept.
Chidi's gonna be our fourth subject.
Chidi can't be part of the experiment.
They already know that he can improve.
That's like studying for a test,
then acing the test.
It's cheating.
How is that cheating?
You're just falsely accusing
us of what you actually did.
No, that's what you're doing.
Shawn, I don't have time for this.
I just started "Deadwood"... finally...
And I need my daily
dose of Timothy Olyphant,
so I'm gonna make this short.
If you so much as breathe
on this experiment again,
I will restart the entire
thing from scratch,
and then I will personally
rip off your eyelids
and make you watch heartwarming videos
of soldiers coming home to their dogs.
Good news: The other four humans
were having so much fun flying,
they didn't see people
being punched out of the sky.
Come on.
Getting Chidi to be one
of the four test subjects,
that's a huge win.
But it doesn't feel like it.
It feels like we got lucky.
And punched in the face.
We also got punched in the face.
Whoa, slow down.
Did you put those trash cans there
just so you could crash into them?
That wasn't my fault, I was texting.
Okay, let him go, dung buckets.
Nice try.
We'll put him on the train
and handcuff him to a bench.
Yeah, forgive us if we don't trust you
not to cheat again.
Surprised you figured
out that Linda was a fake,
because we all thought
you were too stupid.
Well,
it was actually Tahani who got suspicious.
Aww... that is so embarrassing for you.
Seems like you're
royally forking this up,
just like we knew you would.
Okay, take off,
and give Shawn a message for me.
Tell him that we said, "Boo-yah!"
Make sure you do the hand motion.
Like, "Boo-yah!" Are you listening to me?
- Okay, Michael, that's fine.
- No, show me...
- Show me how you're gonna do it.
- That's fine.
No, it's important that
she does the hand thing,
'cause it really drives the point home.